energyplacement.com 2018-01-08

# Energy Jobs, Energy Recruitment Staffing Agency, Engineer Recruiters

Privacy Statement

Effective Date July 13, 2009

Purpose

This statement is made to inform you on the conditions in which personal information is collected and processed in connection with usage of this website.

Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy this notice explains our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

Introduction

You may visit our website without providing any personal information to us. No registration is required to use the website which is open access. If you voluntarily choose to provide us with information, we will only use that information in accordance with the practice outlined in this Privacy Statement and solely for the purpose of recruitment services to you. By providing personal information to us you consent to its collection, use and transfer in accordance with this privacy statement and in accordance with our website terms of use.

What Information Do we Collect

Only where you choose to provide it - we collect non-sensitive personal information such as: Name, Address, Telephone Numbers, Email Address, Education, Qualifications and Employment History for the purposes of recruitment services. (In general you should NEVER send any personal sensitive information)

How Do We Collect Information

We collect information that you send to us via an email, email attached documents (Resume, CV, application supporting documents) and fax transmissions.

Who Collects The Information

Only Energy Placement officers or Energy Placement authorized recruitment executives collect information sent in connection with use of this website.

Why do we collect Information

We collect and process information for the purpose of providing recruitment services to you. Information enables us to provide you with recruitment related information and services including details of current and upcoming job opportunities. Information enables us to match your employment background and skills to current and forthcoming job opportunities so we may alert you to such.

Where is the information held

Information is held in Energy Placement database, on our secured server.

Whom do we share/disclose information with

We may share your information between Energy Placement officers or Energy Placement authorized recruitment executives for the purposes of providing recruitment service to you. We may share your information with a prospective employer as part of the recruitment process - but only on your instruction (see below). We do not share your information with any other party.

Unless required by law, we do not and will not otherwise share, sell or distribute information you provided to us without your consent for any purpose whatsoever, commercial or otherwise.

When/under what circumstances do we share information

We only share information between Energy Placement officers or Energy Placement authorized recruitment executives as we deem necessary to perform a recruitment service to you.

We NEVER submit your Information to a Prospective Employer without first receiving your Express Written/Verbal Consent

We safeguard your interest: Even when you expressly instruct us to submit your candidacy, in the first instance, we will not routinely provide any prospective employer with referee contact information you have sent us. This information should only be required by an employer in the later stages of recruitment (when they have declared a serious intention to move towards appointment) Furthermore, prospective employers (our clients) upon receipt of your information may not contact you directly in the first instance. This is so that we can firstly brief you, and where relevant prepare candidates prior to ANY direct contact from prospective employer. This is to safeguard your privacy and your best interests vis-a-vis current employment.

Security

The nature of the Internet is such that no company can guarantee or warrant the security of any information transmitted to it via the Internet. If you have concerns about transmitting personal information to us over the Internet you should not do so.

However, we take steps to protect your personal information and to safeguard and secure the information we collect. Information is held on our secured server and database. Security measures are in place to protect your information from access by unauthorized persons and against unlawful processing and accidental loss. We will retain information that you have sent to us for a reasonable period for the purposes of providing service to you. We will always take steps to ensure that your information is used in accordance with this policy.

Contacting You

We may contact you at any time, but only if there is a need to do so in connection with a current or immediate job opportunity or potential coming job opportunity. You will not be contacted for any purpose other than recruitment. We will not send you unsolicited commercial communications or contact you for direct marketing purposes. We may periodically send you updates via email to alert you to jobs in our database that match your criteria.

Links

This Website may contain links to other websites or Internet resources. When you visit our website and click on a link to another website you understand that that website will have its own privacy policy where data privacy practices may be different and you may wish to understand how they collect, process and use information.

Log Files

As with most websites, we may collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider) the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

Cookies and Web Beacons

A cookie is a small data file which is sent from a web server to a web browser when that browser visits the server's site. A Web Beacon is a technique used to track who is reading a web page, when, and from what computer.

We do not set, use, implement or control either cookies or web beacons directly on energyplacement.com

However, some third party advertisers on energyplacement.com may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site. Third party advertising companies who serve ads when you visit our website may gather/use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites. These third party advertisers may receive information that includes your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.

Energy Placement does not have any control over, or any responsibility or liability for cookies or other technologies used by third party advertisers, or for any use of, or disclosure of information collected through advertisement cookies or web beacons controlled by these third parties.

Google and the DoubleClick DART cookie

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on energyplacement.com Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our website and other websites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy. You can chose to disable or selectively turn off cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with this website and many other websites that you visit on the internet.

Global

We only allow your personal information to be accessed by energy placement officers or energy placement authorized recruitment executives. Because we operate on an international basis, with prospective employers or clients and candidates residing in countries all over the world, including expatriate candidates, we may require to transfer data between countries. Information you transmit to us may be received, transferred, stored and processed outside of the country in which you reside. In such case we will take steps to ensure that your privacy continues to be protected and information handled as outlined in this privacy statement.

Recruitment Fraud

Recruitment Fraud is a fraud noted by employers worldwide and acknowledged on all major employer websites. Fraud happens where a criminal individual or entity contacts a person in connection with an apparent employment opportunity and where, in order to progress this opportunity for you, they will ask for a payment, or for personal financial information or other personal sensitive information. Typically recruitment fraud takes the form of an email sent to an individual and purporting to come from, or sent on behalf of the employer or potentially purporting to come from, or sent on behalf of a recruitment or staffing agency (like Energy Placement) who act for their client the prospective employer. In addition to asking for money or a payment, these individuals/entities may request sensitive personal information such as personal financial account details, immigration, visa or passport documents, birth certificate, social security number or national identity numbers, credit card numbers etc. This may be via a bogus application form or otherwise.

Energy Placement NEVER requests any kind of payment, fee or processing fee from Job Seekers/Candidates at any time as part of the recruitment process, or for use of our services in anyway howsoever, including for use of our Website.

ALL services to and for Job Seekers/Candidates are provided 100% free

Energy Placement DOES NOT require or request personal sensitive information. NEVER send personal sensitive information.

All official correspondence from Energy Placement Inc comes from, and replies to, an @energyplacement.com email address ONLY.

Notice of Changes to Privacy Statement and Privacy Policy

From time to time we may update this statement and we reserve the right to update our policy/statement at any time. Details of any changes to our privacy statement/policy will be published here, on this web page, and may be accessed from our website using link "Privacy"

Contact

� 2009 Energy Placement Inc. All Rights Reserved
